[{"id": "5ae862267f28483af1e7fdc6", "question": "Who was the author of the novel \"War and Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b718", "question": "Citizens of what empire are credited with starting the tradition of gift giving?", "answer": "Romans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4bb", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Ecuador and Bolivia?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb28bdc9bff04efae6d753", "question": "What year was Mario Puzo's novel \"The Godfather\" published?", "answer": "1969", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedd8836ce05a3942286d6f", "question": "A silhouette of which player is widely recognized as the inspiration behind the official NBA logo designed in 1969?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa35173838c5c8a417f20", "question": "A \"crepuscular\" animal becomes active at what time?", "answer": "Dusk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9f", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Fistmele\"?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c626", "question": "What is the Pleiades?", "answer": "An open star cluster", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffc7e1cf6db9ac4808cff", "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the Air Capital of the World?", "answer": "Wichita, Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7e97db24f84e0b9f9ffce", "question": "What precious metal did alchemists call \"luna\"?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cd", "question": "Who is Freakazoid?", "answer": "Dexter Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af82", "question": "Who died three months into his 4th term as president?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef64996ce05a3942286e67", "question": "What is the smallest theater on Broadway?", "answer": "The Helen Hayes Theatre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe526241bf59ab7d2e380f5", "question": "What is the longest event at the Olympics?", "answer": "Race walk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b393", "question": "Who was the 35th President of the US?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc4416de0eb824d4052f1", "question": "What country's Indigenous name translates to \"Land of the Long White Cloud\"?", "answer": "New Zealand -- In the 1200s, Maori settlers called the North Island \"Aotearoa\", which translates to \"long white cloud\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c8dc877e98cb977789ed", "question": "Which US state is home to Olympic National Park?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe735e8eec85e375820b255", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth trip on as he jumped on the stage of Ford's Theater?", "answer": "Bunting", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d3", "question": "Canada is divided into provinces and what else?", "answer": "Territories", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f4a3aaf848b908361b87b", "question": "What is the name of the tall white hat chefs wear?", "answer": "A Toque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e31", "question": "Who is Miguel Ferrer's mother?", "answer": "Rosemary Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c6", "question": "Where does vanilla come from?", "answer": "Orchids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339676", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Patty and Selma's apartment number?", "answer": "1599", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2e", "question": "What university did David Letterman graduate from in 1969 with a degree in telecommunications?", "answer": "Ball State", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61b", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b743", "question": "What is known as the \"Mary Celeste\"?", "answer": "A ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5b", "question": "What does UFC stand for?", "answer": "Ultimate Fighting Championship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a001", "question": "What British TV series featured Tinky Winky, Dipsy, Laa-Laa, and Po?", "answer": "Teletubbies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339378", "question": "Johann Van der Smut is better known as what?", "answer": "Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601219af63c99d48cd169afa", "question": "From which language did the word \"Ketchup\" come?", "answer": "Chinese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef7", "question": "Whose sensei is a rat named Master Splinter?", "answer": "The Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef91f56ce05a3942286e7e", "question": "Which famous writer had a pet raven named Grip?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338baa", "question": "Which book begins with the words \"It was five o'clock on a winter's morning in Syria\"?", "answer": "Murder on the Orient Express", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339096", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hera?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f97", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983c", "question": "What music awards were founded in 1958?", "answer": "The Grammy Awards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8c", "question": "Which of the 7 dwarves did not speak?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c290", "question": "What is the term for an organism that lives on or in another?", "answer": "Parasite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf01", "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?", "answer": "Sangria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f8a6fa5fdd6dd25324ef", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51cecff04d658268c931f", "question": "What famous general was once attacked by rabbits?", "answer": "Napoleon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389da", "question": "What war saw the bombing of Guernica that inspired one of Picasso's most moving paintings?", "answer": "Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8af1901dd7bf43be5e787", "question": "What causes the holes in Swiss cheese?", "answer": "Bacteria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b497", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8c", "question": "What occupation traditionally referred to its apprentices as \"devils\"?", "answer": "Printers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c7", "question": "What musical character came from the easterly wind with an umbrella and carpet bag?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc9", "question": "Which Apollo 11 astronaut did not set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Michael Collins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590680bdff9c0647b50a808e", "question": "Which character did Anton Yelchin portray in the Star Trek film series reboot, prior to his death in 2016?", "answer": "Pavel Chekov", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5b", "question": "What modern sport grew out of the ancient Thai sport Muay Thai?", "answer": "Kickboxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339245", "question": "What is the birth country of Russell Crowe?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3838815febcc896f927c", "question": "What is the twelfth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a7f64f6f5f79087132fb43", "question": "Which actress who played Alia Atreides in 1984's \"Dune\" and went on to star in 1998's \"Urban Legend\"?", "answer": "Alicia Witt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade7", "question": "In 1944, who was the intended assassination victim of the July 20 Plot?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb81", "question": "What Christian denomination was begun by John Wesley in 1738?", "answer": "Methodist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc67", "question": "What high school did Brett Favre play football for?", "answer": "Hancock North Central", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65916ae7e414034b5aefa", "question": "Pilgrims never called themselves Pilgrims, what were they?", "answer": "Sepratists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab953a86faa38a764be513", "question": "What year did BMW debut the M5?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2146c31a458464a93c456", "question": "When was the last time Easter Sunday and April Fool's Day occurred on the same day in the 20th century?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba2", "question": "Who wrote the children's novel \"Swallows and Amazons\"?", "answer": "Arthur Ransome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942b", "question": "What did John Candy sell in the 1987 movie \"Planes, Trains & Automobiles\"?", "answer": "Shower curtain rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a4", "question": "What is the name of the old gray donkey in Winnie-the-Pooh?", "answer": "Eeyore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb34", "question": "In the late 1990\u2019s, what candy bar used the ad slogan \"Two for me, none for you\"?", "answer": "Twix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60d", "question": "What is the largest mammal in the world?", "answer": "Blue Whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa0201dd7bf43be5e755", "question": "What goes up and down but remains in the same place?", "answer": "Stairs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3de244f0f6af5b066641", "question": "Andorra is part of which continent?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c3", "question": "Which politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d7", "question": "What artist's largest work is called \"The Night Watch\"?", "answer": "Rembrandt's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc92f460f0007efaba0e59", "question": "What is the name of Roy Rogers' horse?", "answer": "Trigger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd95", "question": "What was the pseudonym of famous cross-dresser Amandine-Aurore-Lucile Dupin?", "answer": "George Sand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aaf520565ad31a57c822", "question": "Who was the Supreme Commander of the German Navy from 1943 to 1945?", "answer": "Admiral Karl Dointz (also spelled Doenitz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c6", "question": "French Silk Pie is most commonly flavored with what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add6", "question": "What wonder of the ancient world was destroyed by arson the same night Alexander the Great was born?", "answer": "The Temple of Artemis at Ephesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcc", "question": "What colour is Creme de menthe?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5cad6ce05a3942286e23", "question": "Taylor Swift grew up on what type of farm?", "answer": "Christmas tree farm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b024", "question": "What decisive battle of the Civil War culminated on July 4, 1863 in Mississippi?", "answer": "Battle of Vicksburg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a48b90aac110e416706c", "question": "Zymology, also known as zymurgy, is the study of what?", "answer": "Fermentation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ea4108d98002fdd633a0", "question": "For which film did Anthony Quinn win an Oscar for Best Suporting Actor in 1957?", "answer": "Lust for Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af48", "question": "In which year did Louis Reard invent the bikini?", "answer": "1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62a", "question": "What islands were purchased by the US from Denmark in 1916?", "answer": "US Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8d", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1ac7baab681b09292196", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a461", "question": "The Angkor Wat temple is featured on what Asian country's flag?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5a5f6ce05a3942286e0c", "question": "What was the first videogame system released to be used in conjunction with a television?", "answer": "The Magnavox Odyssey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c790", "question": "What color is the octopus blood?", "answer": "Light blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73e44eec85e375820b273", "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c378", "question": "What tool did Charles Moncke invent?", "answer": "The monkey wrench", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada5", "question": "\"Antonine Plague\" was also known by what other name?", "answer": "Plague of Galen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d14", "question": "What story by Mark Twain involves the characters Tom Canty and Edward, Prince of Wales?", "answer": "The Prince and the Pauper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cbc0877e98cb97778a1e", "question": "In which country is the Casa Rosada?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3e61438e4e5d4832e6306", "question": "Where were the 1940 Summer Olympics scheduled to be held when they were cancelled due to the outbreak of World War II?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898a", "question": "Which Dickens character asked for more?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c1a3877e98cb97778979", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Crossroads of America\"?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb0", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bloody Mary?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397dd", "question": "Which Hollywood Actor was born Issur Danielovitch in 1918?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae25", "question": "In which decade did Yuri Gagarin become the first man to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339539", "question": "What fictional town is the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\" set in?", "answer": "Capeside", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900f", "question": "The composer Berlioz married Harriet Smithson in which year?", "answer": "1833", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f52", "question": "What song begins with the words \"Betty, is that Jimmy's ring you're wearing?\"?", "answer": "Leader of the Pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a04ff048f679a45abe5", "question": "Where is the uvula located?", "answer": "In the throat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339045", "question": "What artist composed the opera \"Tannhauser\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ed", "question": "What was the call sign of Tom Cruise's fighter pilot character in the movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1832baab681b09292187", "question": "Which racing team introduced a six-wheeled race car in 1974 and began racing it in 1976?", "answer": "Tyrrell Racing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5954e8208e82ccaf3b9a67bb", "question": "Whose self-titled debut solo album spent the first of three weeks at #1 on Billboard\u2018s Country album chart?", "answer": "Wynonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7f", "question": "It is considered bad luck to mention what Shakespeare play by name while inside a theater?", "answer": "MacBeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7e", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Dill in the novel \"To Kill a Mockingbird\"?", "answer": "Truman Capote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec89cfec223966ae8f882a", "question": "In which 2000 movie did George Clooney play Captain Billy Tyne?", "answer": "\"A Perfect Storm\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1a7bbaab681b09292194", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cb", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme begin?", "answer": "July 1, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fe", "question": "Whose \"Luncheon of the Boating Party\" prints and posters hung in millions of homes in the 1980's?", "answer": "Pierre-Auguste Renoir's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8f", "question": "Which Protestant Reformer outlawed the Feast of Saint Nicholas in 1545?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e96efe83fe1f2a824be6", "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eac", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"Walk, Don't Run\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a275", "question": "What democratic senator that is a cousin of actress/comedian Amy Schumer?", "answer": "Charles \"Chuck\" Schumer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0c", "question": "Which US president was nicknamed \"His Rotundity\"?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d074f1a1c922dd1ac64b7", "question": "Who was both the 22nd and the 24th president of the United States?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b466e662d71a53650fe9", "question": "Sandro Botticelli's \"Primavera\" features which Roman deity?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600780f8bd51d85e222ab646", "question": "What is the main visual element in Impressionist painting?", "answer": "They were interested in trying to capture the changing effects of light by using a more exact analysis of tone and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c712", "question": "What hormone secreted by the pancreas lowers blood glucose levels in diabetics?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60a", "question": "Which mountain is also known as Monte Cervino and Mont Corvin?", "answer": "The Matterhorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93ae56bd93ce3a4e5f69d", "question": "What scientist's book laid the foundations for classical mechanics?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c4", "question": "Tin cans were invented in 1810, but is it true that can openers did not appear until 50 years later?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa3c86ce05a3942286ea9", "question": "Which famous writer was San Francisco's first Black female streetcar conductor?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "593c4d2db8198b9a2b07796c", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for his portrayal of Jake LaMotta in the film \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ca49877e98cb97778a05", "question": "Which Asian capital was formerly known as Batavia?", "answer": "Jakarta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a6d120565ad31a57c7df", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Postmaster General?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec24148dc25ca9e12ef635", "question": "Whose concerts formed the basis of the documentary film \"Rattle and Hum\"?", "answer": "U2's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe654eaae7e414034b5aead", "question": "Who originally said, \"The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled was convincing man he didn't exist\"?", "answer": "French poet Baudelaire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12f35e39efa6330e0fed7", "question": "Where is the world's shortest commercial runway?", "answer": "Saba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb5ce75dad637d903c8820", "question": "What country is nicknamed \"the land of a thousand lakes\"?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3a", "question": "Prior to getting married, Kate Middleton worked as assistant accessory buyer at what clothing chain?", "answer": "Jigsaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e4", "question": "The group \"April Wine\" was formed in 1969 in what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8dc", "question": "The name for this semi-precious stone comes from the Latin for \"sea water\"?", "answer": "Aquamarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe37a5f0ada16518afdc058", "question": "What two countries declared war on Germany after it invaded Poland?", "answer": "Great Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67c", "question": "Which of the Hawaiian Islands is nicknamed the \"Valley Isle\"?", "answer": "Maui", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b79901dd7bf43be5e7e6", "question": "What country produces the popular treat Tim Tams?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1193d4fea7fe947a2228c", "question": "Which song from the \"White Album\" was originally titled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f0aacee580c7f8fd1e4c", "question": "Who said, \"Tell me and I forget. Teach me and I remember. Involve me and I learn.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3b", "question": "What is actor Anthony Hopkins nationality by birth?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6d", "question": "What purpose did the Colosseum serve when first built?", "answer": "Amphitheatre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a055", "question": "What 1977 film directed by and starring Ron Howard shares its name with a video game series?", "answer": "Grand Theft Auto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ec", "question": "What everyday item did John Walker invent?", "answer": "Friction matches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a08fcad1ec93f27df76e", "question": "What color is pure caffeine?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1683df7c52aae91cc07c4", "question": "What is the fear of light flashes known as?", "answer": "Selaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af987cbaeb0982ee4559554", "question": "What Beatles song is referenced in the opening verse to Bad Company's \"Shooting Star\"?", "answer": "Love Me Do", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9712723c87fd04dd15e4a", "question": "Who is often credited with inventing the thermometer?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975f", "question": "What two murderesses does Billy Flynn represent in Chicago?", "answer": "Velma Kelly and Roxie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b161", "question": "What year was the United Nations found?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32d", "question": "What year was the sequel to the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\" released?", "answer": "1990", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944d", "question": "Who narrates the movie \"Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "Alan Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c275", "question": "What is August's birthstone?", "answer": "Peridot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c89d85011619dd6d415486", "question": "What country\u2019s Royal Wedding was Ike obsessed with in Season 15 of South Park?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc46f6de0eb824d4052f3", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af81", "question": "What was Paul Revere's profession?", "answer": "Silversmith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d4", "question": "What does a red flag mean in auto racing?", "answer": "Stop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdda", "question": "Ash Wednesday marks the first day of what?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b275", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4a46ff048f679a45abc2", "question": "What inventor first used the term \"Horse Power\"?", "answer": "James Watt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339903", "question": "What was the name of the decapitated horse in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9378c6bd93ce3a4e5f670", "question": "Domatophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Houses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3e92f38e4e5d4832e630f", "question": "What was the infamous Bloody Mary's occupation?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cd", "question": "Who played Sofia in the movie \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a109", "question": "Who does Fred Savage play on the TV show \"The Wonder Years\"?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92b", "question": "Where is the Horse racing Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Saratoga Springs, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8fbe501dd7bf43be5e856", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot in it and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65e2b1f3c0ead6880d627", "question": "Who developed world's first color e-book reader?", "answer": "Fujitsu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59524044736d4be723796b60", "question": "What island is the most populous in Canada?", "answer": "Island of Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cb2b877e98cb97778a16", "question": "Acapulco is a city in which Mexican state?", "answer": "Guerrero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596761662b59efe0e9417ea3", "question": "What country music artist was nicknamed \"Chief\" after his maternal grandfather, who was Chief of Police?", "answer": "Eric Church", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3e9eff048f679a45ab5c", "question": "High blood pressure is also known as what?", "answer": "Hypertension", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a33", "question": "What do sisters Elinor and Marianne Dashwood represent in the title of a Jane Austen novel?", "answer": "Sense and Sensibility", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8d", "question": "Francis Scott Key wrote what famous song?", "answer": "The Star Spangled Banner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac81", "question": "What year did the red maple leaf design officially become Canada's flag?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed2", "question": "What happened to Barry Allen after lightning struck the chemicals in his lab?", "answer": "He turned into the Flash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a939", "question": "What two colors are in the flag of Austria?", "answer": "Red and white", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe733d9eec85e375820b226", "question": "What was the code name for the Battle of Okinawa?", "answer": "Operation Iceberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab5", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Angola?", "answer": "Red-crested turaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abd", "question": "Who played the Vice-President of the US in the 1997 movie \"Air Force One\"?", "answer": "Glenn Close", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d44", "question": "What year was artist Claude Monet born in?", "answer": "1840", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ad", "question": "When did J. D. Salinger publish the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b1", "question": "What year did the Jallianwahla Bagh massacre occur?", "answer": "1919", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8c6cec223966ae8f8849", "question": "What is Alastor Moody's nickname?", "answer": "Mad Eye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c8c7877e98cb977789ec", "question": "Where is the Sphinx Observatory located?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae864587f28483af1e7fdce", "question": "How many countries share common borders with India?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f74", "question": "Who was the first novelist to present a typed manuscript to his publisher?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe938326bd93ce3a4e5f67f", "question": "Hydrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339412", "question": "On the \"Abbey Road\" album cover, which member of the Beatles is on the far left?", "answer": "George Harrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dd", "question": "What organ of the body is particularly affected by hepatitis?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a683", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Treasure State\"?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fe", "question": "The surface of the dwarf planet Pluto is made largely of what type of frozen gas?", "answer": "Methane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b29", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was always causing trouble for Ranger Smith?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389dd", "question": "What English writer died on the on the same date as Spanish author and poet Miguel de Cervantes?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd662c7a5bfecdd737e0848", "question": "What was Princess Diana's title before she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "Lady Diana Spencer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8a", "question": "What must be manufactured by Victorinox or Wenger to be official?", "answer": "Swiss Army knives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77365eec85e375820b306", "question": "What country has the largest forest found within a city?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bf6c877e98cb97778967", "question": "What is the largest flat-topped mountain in the world?", "answer": "Grand Mesa in Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a8", "question": "What musical's show-stopping songs include \"Mr. Cellophane\" and \"Razzle Dazzle\"?", "answer": "Chicago's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9ba81364247bf200fb898", "question": "Which political party was co-founded in West Germany in 1979 by the late Petra Kelly?", "answer": "The Green Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b942", "question": "What are spit in the annual contest in Paul's Valley, Oklahoma?", "answer": "Watermelon seeds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b612", "question": "In baseball, which number references the shortstop?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b0", "question": "In 2001, who gave the first concert in Oslo's Vallhall football arena?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad87", "question": "Who proposed the idea of \"Laissez-faire\"?", "answer": "Adam Smith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339adf", "question": "What Beatles title character \"wears a face which she keeps in a jar by the door\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Rigby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a7c490aac110e4167089", "question": "What important property do cider apples have that most eating and cooking apples don\u2019t?", "answer": "High sugar content", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25eec56682715b82711cd0", "question": "What year did Spain start to colonize Venezuela?", "answer": "1522", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ec", "question": "What musical instrument appears on the Guinness beer label?", "answer": "Harp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfcbf9616e6c6d4eba4f2", "question": "What kid's show that contains the song \"We Are Number One\" ran from 2004-2014?", "answer": "Lazy Town", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339390", "question": "What is the name of the third Austin Powers movie?", "answer": "Austin Powers in Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac96", "question": "Who was Elizabeth I's father?", "answer": "Henry VIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec85e4ec223966ae8f880b", "question": "What is the name of the first videogame in the \"Warcraft\" series?", "answer": "\"Orcs & Humans\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a633", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peace Garden State\"?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c4d3877e98cb977789a7", "question": "What is the only country with coasts on the Persian Gulf and the Caspian Sea?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfbaa8003d27d341092bc4", "question": "What are Easter Island's famous statues called?", "answer": "Moai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b24c", "question": "Whom did the Daughters of the American Revolution bar from singing at Constitution Hall in 1936?", "answer": "Marian Anderson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338982", "question": "What Verdi opera includes the popular \"La donna e mobile\"?", "answer": "Rigoletto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d116e14fea7fe947a22274", "question": "From what Gaelic word is \"Dublin\" derived?", "answer": "Dublind", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d0", "question": "What was the last desktop computer made by Commodore?", "answer": "The Amiga 4000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad33", "question": "What country became third in the world to test an atom bomb in 1952?", "answer": "Great Britain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a797", "question": "Havana is located on which side of Cuba?", "answer": "The west", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6ab0820565ad31a57c823", "question": "Who was the commander of German U-boats from 1939 to 1943?", "answer": "Admiral Karl Dointz (also spelled Doenitz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84e", "question": "Jackson Hole ski resort is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c5", "question": "In 1643 Evangalista Torichelli invented the first what?", "answer": "Barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5a", "question": "What sea does the river Elbe flow into?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69c", "question": "The \"Boss of the Plains\" was a type of what?", "answer": "A hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb57cf5dad637d903c880b", "question": "Which famed explorer was born in Venice and now lends his name to Venice's main airport?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f43601dd7bf43be5e81f", "question": "In the business world, NASDAQ stands for what?", "answer": "National Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a039", "question": "What is Quagmire's daughter's name in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Anna Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd8a8e347d002c297e4c8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Icarus' father?", "answer": "Daedalus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd94", "question": "In 2002, Sony ended production of its recorders using what doomed video standard?", "answer": "Betamax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba30", "question": "What is the Hawaiian word for \"hello\"?", "answer": "Aloha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b536", "question": "What does an archer carry his arrows in?", "answer": "A Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339322", "question": "In \"Home Alone\", what animal did Buzz keep as a pet?", "answer": "A tarantula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25ee9e6682715b82711cce", "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?", "answer": "The Dutch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff20fdb31a458464a93c437", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Tarzan of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922c", "question": "What New York City night spot was the subject of a 1984 Richard Gere movie?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa80", "question": "What is the nickname for Reading, Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Pretzel City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ed", "question": "What element makes your pee smell after you eat asparagus?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c633", "question": "What are the twin stars in the constellation of Gemini called?", "answer": "Pollux and Castor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f6f36a9e54d890926f6cf", "question": "Which U.S. state has an official state cookie called biscochito?", "answer": "New Mexico -- Brought to the\u00a0region by 16th-century Spanish colonists, it is a shortbread cookie flavored with cinnamon and anise.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894d", "question": "What William Golding novel tells the story of a group of boys cast away on a desert island?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b026", "question": "What Native American leader surrendered at Skeleton Canyon in 1886?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}]